Santhosh Kumar Gaja

Senior Associate

gajasanthoshkumar@gmail.com • +919652982523

LinkedIn • Hyderabad, India

Disciplined and insightful data analyst with 4+ years of business process analysis experience. With over 3 years of professional

experience in the IT industry, working on Power BI Desktop, Power BI Service and SQL Server. Experience with Microsoft Business Intelligence Suite (Power Query, PowerPivot, Power View, Power BI Desktop, Power BI Service). Imported data from multiple data sources into BI tools, created relationships between data, created calculated columns and measures using DAX Query. Working with the star schema is the simplest form of a dimensional model, in which data is organized into facts and dimensions.

Technical Proficiencies

Programming Microsoft Power BI, Tableau Desktop, Advanced Excel, AWS, SQL, Python (Basics) and Data Analysis

Languages: Expression.

SSMS, Power Query and Visual Studio. **IDE**:

Career Experience

Wipro Technologies, Hyderabad

2020 - Present

Senior Associate

- Create reports and dashboards in Power BI desktop to provide visibility to senior management that supports data-driven decisions
- Measures and calculated columns generated using Dax functions such as ALL, Calculate, Filter, DateDiff, Date ADD, Calendar, etc.
- Use of Power BI, Power Pivot to develop data analysis prototype, and use of Power View and Power Map to visualize reports.
- Build row-level security with Power BI and integrate with the Power BI service portal.
- Explore data in different ways and through multiple visualizations using Power BI
- Reports and dashboards published using Power BI.
- Using parameters for Dynamic level filters.
- Create formatting, advanced formatting in tooltip labels such as descriptive tooltips and conditional formatting.
- Working with Power BI personal gateways and enterprise gateways.
- Work on larger data sets for data analysis using Pivot Tables, Power Query, Power Pivot.
- Summarize and extract key information in Excel and in Power BI
- Work with bookmarks, buttons, selection pane, filters.
- Have experience in creating new metrics for YTD, MTD, QTD growth analysis in Power Desktop.
- Work with filters like page, visual, report and drill down filters.
- Prepare ad-hoc reports on customer cancellations, customer additions, response and resolution SLAs in service delivery area.
- Involved in the preparation of ad hoc, weekly, monthly and quarterly presentations across operations and service delivery teams.
- Involved in daily scrums and bi-weekly meetings.

Cognizant Technologies, Hyderabad

2018 - 2020

Software Process Executive - Data (2018 – 2020)

- Experience in development of Reports, Dashboards in Power Bl.
- Generated Calculated Measures & Columns using Dax. Dax Functions like ALL, Calculate, Filter, DateDiff etc.
- Used Power BI, Power Pivot to develop data analysis prototype, and used Power View and Power Map to visualize reports.
- Publishing the data source into Power BI Server and scheduling the data sources.
- Explore data in a variety of ways and across multiple visualizations using Power BI
- Published reports and dashboards using Power BI.
- Worked on larger datasets for Analysing data by using Pivot tables, Power Query, Power Pivot.
- Summarizing and extracting key insights in Excel & in Power BI
- Working with Bookmarks, Buttons, Selection Pane, Filters.
- Strong user interface design skills and data visualization.

- Using Pivot Table, Power Pivot, Lookup functions, Filters & Sorting Techniques
- Creating Tables and Charts for preparing Quality objective chart for each and every assembly.
- Handling multiple reports, working with formulae, pivot tables & pivot charts, and various other excel sheet components for accurate data.

Amazon, Hyderabad 2017 – 2018

Network Operations Specialist (2017 – 2018)

- Demonstrate critical thinking and attention to detail review customer's concern and investigate on the ticket and follow up with exact solution to it
- Test new procedures and files in a product incubation environment which may assist with future workflow process for specialized products
- Participate in weekly meetings and perform other duties as assigned

GlobalLogic Technologies, Hyderabad

2016 - 2017

Associate Analyst (2016 – 2017)

- Maintained MIS for performance characteristics involving preparing reports for process vise and sharing daily productivity reports with respective teams.
- Developed effective dialogue to share issues and information with superiors, peers, and business partners to accomplish our joined business goals.
- Preparing dashboards and maintaining attrition data and Billing's data for the projects.
- Assisted in development and preparation of reports describing trends, expenses and tracking of workflow.
- Reviewed and evaluated department and unit performance to prepare stacks for monthly, quarterly & yearly.

Education

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering

MallaReddy Institute of Eng.